Felipe de Moraes Modesto

CARFER SUMMARY

I am a game developer with a decade of experience in the industry. Currently a Game Programmer & Coordinator at Ludia Inc. Current responsibilities includes game feature development, editor tools development, prototyping, requirements analysis, planning, supervising programmer work and project flow as well as R&D on machine learning and other endeavours in artificial intelligence. I currently reside in Montreal and am a permanent resident of Canada.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ludia - 2019-Current

- ♦ (2019-Current) Programming Coordinator
- ♦ (2019-Current) Game Programmer

Fira Soft - 2011-2018

- ♦ (2014-2018) Game Programmer & Production Lead Working Remotely
- ♦ (2011-2014) Game Programmer & Creative Director

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Programming

C#, Python, C++, Lua, Java, JavaScript, R, Linux Shell, SQL (MySQL & SQLite)

Tools & Frameworks

Unity3D, Mobile Development, Corona SDK, Android Studio, IceScrum, Google Analytics, rStudio, ADB, OBS

Process

Scrum (IceScrum), Git/Mercurial (GitHub / Bitbucket / Gitlab), GDD

NOTABLE WORKS

Untitled Disney Project (In Development) - Mobile - Unity3D

Role: Gameplay feature programming, programmer coordination, tool programming, artificial intelligence & machine learning, scrum lead.

Kriophobia (in Development) - PC / PS4 - Unity3D

Role: Feature programming, project management, art management& asset validation, design documentation production.

SEVeN - Network Simulator - PC - OMNet++

Role: Architecture design, protocol stack implementation, debugging, data analysis, production of technical reports& other academic material.

NeuroVR (VR Patient Cognitive Evaluation Tool) - PC - Unity3D

Role: Project management, client interaction, feature programming, debugging, interface and usability design, patient evaluation metric design.

Move-it! Charades - Mobile - Corona SDK

Role: Gameplay feature implementation, gameplay feature design, core feature implementation, UI/UX design, publishing and maintaining store presence, game content production.

Multiple papers published in Academic Conferences and Journals

Role: Academic research proposal, implementation, analysis and document production Plase access google scholar page for a mostly complete list of publications.

CONTACT

felipe@modesto.io +1 (438) 409-2898 Montreal QC, Canada

BIO

Education

DOCTOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Ottawa 2014-2018

Languages

- English Native
- ♦ French A2
- ⋄ Portuguese Native

Traits

- Natural Leader
- ♦ Team Player
- Multitasker
- ⋄ Perfectionist

INTERESTS

Roles

- ♦ Lead Game Programmer
- Senior Game Programmer
- Software Engineer
- ⋄ Research Engineer

Career

- Data Analysis
- Automation
- ⋄ Networks
- Graphics

Personal

- ♦ Board Games
- Mechanical Keyboards
- Plotting Graphs
- Curious Facts

LINKS

Github: felipemodesto Twitter: felipemodesto Linkedin: femodesto Scholar: Felipe Modesto

More details available at: www.modesto.io